Mss.Rec.23 Mss.Rec.23
American Philosophical Society
Penobscot Indian language study
1956
Mss.Rec.23
American Philosophical Society
1.0 Tape(s)
Penobscot songs and dance, plus five untranslated spoken texts. Arthur Neptune, consultant. Recorded in June 1956, most likely in Maine.
1 sound tape reel (22 min.); analog, 3 3/4 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
Gordon, Eugene
Neptune, Arthur
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Eugene Gordon. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Penobscot Indians; Penobscot Indians--Music; Penobscot language; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Penobscot Text No. 1, 1956-06; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:07; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Penobscot Indians; Penobscot language
  - Penobscot Text No. 2, 1956-06; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:46; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
  - Penobscot Text No. 3, 1956-06; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:21; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
  - Penobscot Text No. 4, 1956-06; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:43; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
  - Penobscot Text No. 5, 1956-06; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:57; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
  - A Thanksgiving Song, 1956-06; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
    Penobscot Indians; Penobscot Indians--Music
  - A Chant Coming Down the River in Canoes, 1956-06; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
    Penobscot Indians--Music; Penobscot language
  - Tomahawk Dance, 1956-06; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur
  - Bow and Arrow Dance, 1956-06; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:25; Gordon, Eugene S.; Neptune, Arthur